Oh everyone, welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we
have a very romantic dialogue for you.
That's right, today we are at a shop and we
are buying jewelry, so of course there are
many different types
of jewelry and stones, so
we're going to take a
look at all that great stuff.
Let's jump into our dialogue
and see what's going on.
Good afternoon sir, is there
anything I can help you with today?
Yeah, I'm looking
for a nice gift to give
my girlfriend, our fifth
anniversary is next Friday.
Well I would be happy to assist you
in choosing the perfect gift for her.
Is there anything in particular
that you have in mind?
No, not really, I'm completely out of loss.
Well, you can give her
a set of pearl earrings,
or this beautiful
heart-shaped pendant.
What is her favorite gemstone?
That purple one, I'm
sorry I've never bought
jewelry for anyone
and I'm kind of nervous.
Don't worry, we specialize
in providing our customers
a relaxed, pressure-free
shopping environment.
That stone is an amethyst.
We have a range of
beautiful amethyst pieces.
Look at this bracelet, it's 18 carat rose
gold studded with amethyst and blue topaz.
It's a great statement piece.
Oh wow, that's really
pretty, just would love
that, but I was thinking of something a
little more delicate, perhaps a necklace.
We have this beautiful platinum pendant,
or you could also get her a lock it.
You could also get her a timepiece,
it's both glamorous and functional.
If you tell me a little
more about your
girlfriend, maybe I can help
you find something for her.
Yes, well, she's very smart, she's a
great sense of humor, she's very feminine.
Perhaps you could give her a ring?
Well, actually, I was
thinking about asking
just to marry me, I've
just been so nervous.
Well, sir, I believe your fifth
anniversary is a great time to propose.
Okay, I've decided I'm
going to pop the question.
Fabulous, we should look
at engagement rings then.
Now that's a whole other section.
All right, we're back, so now let's
take a look at the language takeaway.
In language takeaway,
we have a lot of
jewelry words and terms for you,
so let's take a look at some of these.
The first one I want to talk
about Marco is pearl earrings.
That's right.
The sales assistant offered
a set of pearl earrings.
So we have earrings that you wear on your
ears, usually girls, but what about pearl?
Pearls are a kind of decoration
that comes from inside an animal.
The clam is a sea animal that opens up
and inside there might be a little pearl.
It's usually a white or
pink, very, very pretty
object, and we sometimes put
them in earrings or on a necklace.
That's right.
So a set of pearl earrings
or earrings that have this
little rock or this little
marble looking thing on it.
And well, he also offered a
beautiful, hard-shaped pendant.
Okay, a pendant is a
kind of necklace and
basically a pendant is
something that hangs down.
So in this case, it's a
necklace that might
have something on the bottom that
hangs down like in the shape of a heart.
So that's what heart-shaped means.
It means that it has the shape of a heart.
For example, you can
have a heart-shaped cake.
You can also have a heart-shaped face.
Okay, very good.
And of course, the pendant is a little
thing that hangs from the necklace.
Now maybe some pendants can also
have a gemstone, and that's our next word.
So a gemstone is not just a normal stone.
It's a beautiful, normally expensive stone.
And we often have gemstones
that relate to a person's birthday.
Right.
So these come in many
different colors and types.
The two that we heard about in
today's dialogue are purple and blue.
That's right.
The one that you're
talking about is the
one that the shop assistant
suggested, which is amethyst.
Amethyst is a purple stone.
It's really, really pretty,
and it's sometimes
lights, but I'm so
a little bit darker.
It depends on the one
that you're looking at.
But amethyst is a little bit difficult
to say, but it's a kind of gemstone.
The other one we heard
about is called Topaz.
Okay, a Topaz, and this one is blue.
So I guess they all look very much like
diamonds, but they are different colors.
So Topaz looks like a blue diamond kind of.
Right.
And ruby is red.
Very good.
I think there's a black
one that's called Onyx.
Onyx is black.
That's right.
Okay.
So many different types of gemstones.
And as Catherine said, usually,
each month has a specific gemstone.
So that's considered your gemstone
if you were born on that month.
Exactly.
All right.
Now moving on to our next word,
we have another type of jewelry
that usually hangs from a
necklace, just like a pendant.
But on this occasion, it's a lock it.
Okay.
A lock it is something that usually
women will wear around their necks.
Now this is like a pendant, but it opens.
So it's something that can open up.
And sometimes people
have photographs inside.
Many times they're shaped
like a heart or a book.
And inside, you can see a picture
or a note, something very personal.
Okay.
Very good.
So it's very similar to a pendant,
but as you said, it opens up.
You see it all the time
in movies, people have
pendants and inside to have
a nice picture or of someone.
That's right.
That's a lock it.
All right.
Very good.
I think we've taken a look at a
lot of vocab related to jewelry here.
Why don't we go back, let's review
this dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
Good afternoon, sir.
Is there anything I can
help you with today?
Yeah.
I'm looking for a nice
gift to give my girlfriend.
Our fifth anniversary is next Friday.
Well, I would be happy to assist
you in choosing the perfect gift for her.
Is there anything in particular
that you have in mind?
No.
Not really.
I'm completely out of loss.
Well, you can give her
a set of pearl earrings
or this beautiful
heart-shaped pendant.
What is her favorite gemstone?
That purple one.
I'm sorry.
I've never bought jewelry for
anyone and I'm kind of nervous.
Don't worry, we specialize
in providing our customers
a relaxed, pressure-free
shopping environment.
That stone is an amethyst.
We have a range of
beautiful amethyst pieces.
Take a look at this bracelet.
It's 18 carat rose gold studded
with amethyst and blue topaz.
It's a great statement piece.
Oh, wow.
That's really pretty.
Just would love that.
I was thinking of something a little
more delicate, perhaps a necklace.
We have this beautiful platinum pendant
or you could also get her a lock it.
You could also get her a timepiece.
It's both glamorous and functional.
If you tell me a little
more about your
girlfriend, maybe I can help
you find something for her.
Yes.
Well, she's very smart.
She's a great sense of humor.
She's very feminine.
Perhaps you could give her a ring.
Well, actually, I was thinking
about asking just to marry me.
I've just been so nervous.
Well, sir.
I believe your fifth anniversary
is a great time to propose.
OK, I've decided.
I'm going to pop the question.
Fabulous.
We should look at engagement rings, then.
Now, that's a whole other section.
All right, we're back, so now
let's take a look at fluency builder.
So the first phrase in
fluency builder today
comes from the
beginning of our dialogue,
where Mark says to the shop assistant,
listen, I'm completely at a loss.
OK, so what does he mean when he told
the shopkeeper, I'm completely at a loss.
At a loss means I have no idea.
I'm really confused.
OK.
All right, I need help.
So if a teacher asks you a
questioning, you don't know the answer.
You can say, I'm sorry, I'm at a loss.
I'm at a loss.
Or when I see someone and
they say, hi, how you doing?
I say, oh, I'm so embarrassed.
I'm really at a loss.
I don't remember your name.
OK, very good.
So I'm at a loss.
Now when Mark was
describing his girlfriend,
Jess, he said, well, she's very smart
and has a great sense of humor.
OK, so sense of humor is
characteristic that we give to people.
So he has no sense of humor,
or she has a great sense of humor.
And this means that
this person likes to tell
jokes and is funny and
enjoys a good time, really.
So it means that this person is not really
that serious or always angry or unhappy.
No, not an overly serious person.
It generally means that the person is
good at telling jokes and makes you laugh.
OK, so Jess has a good sense of humor.
And because of all
these things and they've
been together for five
years, Mark says, OK,
I've decided I'm going
to pop the question.
OK, this might sound very strange
because you think, well, pop the question.
What is the question?
Well, in English, the phrase pop the
question has a very special meaning.
It means to ask someone to marry you.
So if I say, I'm going
to pop the question,
that means I'm going to
ask someone to marry me.
That's right.
Or you could say, he'd
popped the question last night.
We're engaged.
OK, so that means to ask me to marry him.
OK, all right, so it's a
phrase to pop the question.
So whenever you use it together, you're
talking about asking someone to marry you.
Exactly.
All right, great stuff.
Why don't we go back and
listen to this dialogue one last time.
Good afternoon, sir.
Is there anything I can
help you with today?
Yeah, I'm looking for a
nice gift to give my girlfriend.
Our fifth anniversary is next Friday.
Well, I would be happy to assist
you in choosing the perfect gift for her.
Is there anything in particular
that you have in mind?
No, not really.
I'm completely out of loss.
Well, you can give her
a set of pearl earrings
or this beautiful
heart-shaped pendant.
What is her favorite gemstone?
That purple one.
I'm sorry.
I've never bought jewelry for
anyone, and I'm kind of nervous.
Don't worry.
We specialize in
providing our customers a
relaxed, pressure-free
shopping environment.
That stone is an amethyst.
We have a range of
beautiful amethyst pieces.
Take a look at this bracelet.
It's 18 carat rose gold studded
with amethyst and blue topaz.
It's a great statement piece.
Oh, wow.
That's really pretty.
Just would love that.
I was thinking of something a little
more delicate, perhaps a necklace.
We have this beautiful platinum pendant,
or you could also get her a locket.
You could also get her a timepiece.
It's both glamorous and functional.
If you tell me a little
more about your
girlfriend, maybe I can help
you find something for her.
Yes?
Well, she's very smart.
She's a great sense of humor.
She's very feminine.
Perhaps you could give her a ring.
Well, actually, I was thinking
about asking just to marry me.
I've just been so nervous.
Well, sir.
I believe your fifth anniversary
is a great time to propose.
Okay, I've decided.
I'm going to pop the question.
Fabulous.
We should look at engagement rings then.
Now that's a whole other section.
So talking about jewelry
and all of these gemstones,
we also took a look
at different metal types.
We talked about gold, which is, I think,
one of the most popular types of metals.
That's right.
It's kind of like a yellow color.
Now when we talk about
gold, we talk about 14
carat, 18 carat, 24
carat, stuff like this.
Yeah.
So the carat, usually it's
abbreviated like a K18K 14K.
It means how pure the gold is.
Okay.
Actually, they also use it in diamonds.
They talk about a diamond
that's one carat or two carats.
Right.
So in diamonds, it has a different meaning.
It actually means how
much the diamond weighs.
So some engagement rings
are half a carat or a carat.
And they're really, really
big ones are like two carats.
And those are very expensive.
That's right.
And we also saw another metal here
platinum, which is a very nice metal.
It looks like silver, but it's stronger.
It's much stronger.
So you can hit something
and it won't leave an impression.
It won't change the look of the metal.
And this is very, this
is very popular right
now for wedding bands,
you know, those rings
that men and women
get after they're married.
Many people like to get this
silvery looking platinum ring.
I've actually seen different
types of metals that
weren't mentioned into
dialogue like titanium rings.
Titanium is also a very
strong metal or I can
remember this metal,
but it's used on spacecraft
and it's very, very strong,
stronger than titanium.
I don't know what it is.
And yeah, they also
make rings out of it,
but another interesting thing is
some people make their own rings.
They're wedding bands
or they're wedding rings.
I've seen that.
It's a very nice thing to do, I
think, because it's meaningful.
People like to do it
together and then they
have these rings that
are very special for them.
So a person that makes jewelry or
makes rings is called a jeweler, right?
A jeweler.
That's right.
So I have a friend who is a jeweler,
he makes beautiful rings and earrings.
Okay.
So not only rings, a person that makes
jewelry in general can be called a jeweler.
Exactly.
All right.
A very interesting topic,
especially for the girls who
always love to have rings
and diamonds and necklaces.
For the boys, I know
some boys really like
to get earrings or to
have jewelry like a...
I've never really seen too many
guys wearing necklaces though.
A lot of guys wear cross necklaces,
I've seen, or rings, not too many rings.
I don't think it's a big thing.
I'm a lot of American guys wear rings.
Oh yeah.
I think, well, not a lot, but some do.
So well, obviously it's
popular all around and of
course we are interested
in hearing from you guys.
So if you have any
questions or any other
suggestions about this lesson or anything,
you can always find us at EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you guys there.
Bye.
[music]